The Psychological Significance of the "Bible" Story The first introduction to the concept of "God" Jordan B. Peterson
The translations used in this subtitle when referring to the original text of the "Bible" are based on the "Mandarin Chinese Union Version" ("God" version)
The Psychological Significance of "Bible" Stories Dr. Jordan B. Peterson First Lecture May 16, 2017
Thank you all for coming
What surprised me was
Everyone really has nothing to do on Tuesday night
It's really weird in a way
So many people come to listen
A series of lectures on the psychological significance of "Bible" stories
I have wanted to do this for a long time
But what surprised me was that someone would be willing to listen
That’s great, let’s take one step at a time
I want to start with this because the question is very reasonable
Why bother to do this
I don’t mean why you should take this effort
I have my own reasons
But you might think
Why bother with this strange ancient book
This is a good question
This contradictory document has been pieced together into a book for thousands of years
It survives beyond countless kingdoms
This is really interesting. A book is tougher than a rock
It can withstand the test of time than castles and empires
This is really interesting
Something so fleeting will last so long
So this is like a mystery
This is how I look at the "Bible" story
They are like a mystery
Because basically they are
There are many things we don’t understand
We don't know how they came from
We don’t understand how they pieced together
We don't know why
They will have such an incredible influence on civilization
We don’t understand why people still believe these stories
We don’t know what it means to not believe them now
Or we don’t even know
If we believe what these stories mean
There is another problem
This question is not limited to me but must be related to me
That is no matter how high your education is
You can't accumulate enough knowledge to discuss
The Psychological Significance in the Story of the Bible
But i will do my best
Partly because I want to learn more about them
as far as I know
One of the best ways to learn something is to tell
I am also thinking during my lecture
I'm not trying to tell you the facts I am convinced
Because there are many things I'm not sure about
I'm just trying to clarify the truth
And I’ve been doing this for a long time
You may or may not know that I admire Nietzsche
Nietzsche is a powerful critic of dogmatic Christianity
This refers to the situation when Christianity was realized by institutions
Yet he is a paradoxical thinker
Nietzsche once said such a thing
He doesn’t believe if it’s not because of Christianity
The scientific revolution will begin or succeed
To be precise, this refers to Catholicism
He believes that in the course of a thousand years of history
Europeans have trained their way of thinking into
Explain everything in
In a single coherent framework
If you accept the initial axiom, it is coherent
A single coherent framework
Nietzsche believed that the Catholicization of life and historical phenomena
Gave birth to a way of thinking that can surpass
Its dogmatic foundation and focus on other things
In this case it happens to be the natural world
Nietzsche felt that Christianity was buried in his own hands
And it took a long time to try to go
Make people aware of the need for truth
Keep people from falling
And the fall is often part of human attempts
The spirit of truth is developed from Christianity
But it also counteracts the foundation of Christianity
Everyone mutters or thinks after waking up
Why do we start to believe these things
It's like one day you wake up and find
You really don’t know why a Christmas tree is erected
But you have been doing this for a long time
And this is often the behavior of people
The Christmas tree appeared for a reason
After the cause is forgotten, the ceremony still exists
Nietzsche is not only a critic of Christianity
Is also a champion of its discipline
Another thing Nietzsche agrees with is
You cannot be free if you were not a slave
He meant to say
You will not leap from childhood to mature adult personality
You will move from childhood to a state of discipline
This can be understood as similar to self-imposed slavery
This will be the best situation
Before you can regain the generality of childhood
You must discipline yourself to be a certain individual
He believes that Christianity is
Played such a role for Western civilization
But at the end of the 19th century he declared "God is dead"
You will often hear this sentence in a triumphant tone
But not for Nietzsche
He is far from such a simple thinker
Nietzsche is clear and this is what I want to clarify
That’s the structure of experience we still don’t know much
We don't understand reality
What we have is a clear statement of the world
We know nothing beyond this
There is a buffer zone in this
This is what we seem to know
But we don’t have a clear understanding of it
for example
When you are arguing with your relatives and friends, it coincides with a low mood
They become sensitive, irritable and unreasonable
If you keep talking
They may suddenly stand up and even cry
When they started crying
They can understand why they are angry
And it's not because of you
Although you might have caused this controversy
In my opinion this is a very interesting phenomenon
Because it means that people can understand others to a certain extent
But it is difficult to express in words
In a sense, the mind is sublimated from the body
It affects emotional video and behavior
Before we recognize a thing clearly
I can already understand it on a certain level
We have a space that can be clearly explained
Where we can discuss everything
But outside of this we are in contact with
Something similar to a dream we will get stuck in it
What we are trapped in is an emotional dream
And it is based at least in part on our behavior
I will describe this later
We don’t know anything beyond this part
This dream is where the mystics and artists live
They are the medium between the omniscience and the unknown
This means that what we know is based on
The form of knowledge that we don’t actually understand
If the two are not consistent
If we can articulate the knowledge
If it's out of sync with our dreams
Then we will tear from the inside
What we think, what we do, what we don’t dream
This will cause a mental disorder
This mental disorder
And its antidote is something like a
Belief and representation
People will turn to things like ideology
This seems to me to be attached to
Parasites based on underlying religion
In order to organize their thoughts
This disaster was what Nietzsche had foreseen
He realized
When we destroy representations
When stripping away the foundation of Western civilization
This representation refers to the ideal model of God
We will become unstable
Sway between nihilism and ideological extremes
He is especially concerned about the radical left ideology
And it was predicted as early as the end of the 19th century
This is really a shocking insight
There will be hundreds of millions of deaths in the 20th century
It is precisely because it replaces this dreamlike structure that is hidden at the bottom
Replaced by rational
But the extremely wrong way of expressing the world
We have been swinging back and forth between left and right ever since
With sporadic nihilism and despair
In a sense, this is the situation of modern Westerners
All humanity is gradually falling into it
I think islam
Part of the reason for being hostile to the West is
There are many other reasons and not all of them are justified
It is certain that one of the reasons is
Because they are still based on dreams
So they can see that the West has nothing to trust
Doubtful thinking
And this threatens the integrity of their culture
And it is true
We westerners have been racking our brains to destroy the Great Wall
I'm not complaining
It’s not easy to deal with this situation
But this disaster is not without results
It has a real impact on people’s lives
This is not very abstract
For example, I have seen and treated many times
Found in patients with depression or anxiety
They are all in an existential crisis
This is not just as simple as mental illness
Their abnormality is not only caused by neurochemical disorders
Although sometimes it happens to be the reason
And the reason is that they have been
Overwhelmed by the pain and complexity of his life
And they are not sure if it makes sense to continue
You can feel the bad negative meaning in life
So I doubt that I believe it has any positive meaning
I have a client who is a very good artist
As long as he doesn't think, he's fine
He will create
And he is really good at his job
His personality is to keep creating great products
But he always underestimates himself
Self-destruct
But when he started thinking about what he did
It seems to use a drill, saw or similar to break the road
He will start to criticize what he did
Think his job is useless
Although the value of his work is obvious
So he found it difficult to find motivation to create
As a reason and being
A great example of the consequences of a split in some way
He impressed me
He split to truly doubt his own existence value
This is really not a joke
Its seriousness lies in what it shows
Not only an individual's mental illness
And it's also a mental illness of society
The tendency of people to get involved in ideology
In my opinion it is a lame religion
This is the right way to understand them
They are like a religion lacking arms and legs
But still forge ahead
It creates a sense of security and group identity
But it’s deformed and crazily surly
And parasitic on some potential richness and reality
In short, this is how I look at it
I think it’s important to solve this problem
I think nothing
It's more urgent than this
I have been thinking about this for a long, long time
I have been researching since the 80s
The belief system is regulating
Role in mental and social health
You can realize that it does work
Because when you challenge people’s belief systems
They will be really upset
Why do they care so much
Even your ideological principles
What if it is completely correct
Let’s put it this way when people’s ideological principles are pointed out
Will become very angry
Even if I exhaust my imagination, I can’t find the obvious reason
They are based on a basic truth
They are like on a raft in the middle of the sea
When you start to pull the wooden slats from the raft
They will be afraid of falling and drowning
What drowned
What is the raft protecting them from?
Why they are so afraid
Beyond the boundaries of ideology
These are not obvious things
I have tried to solve this mystery for a long time
There are some videos of my lectures on this topic on YouTube
Most of you know it
Part of the content in this series of lectures
You have heard of it
If you watch those videos
But I want to try to explain from some other angles
Nietzsche’s view is human
Is to create its own value
He knows we all have bodies
Motivation and emotion
In a way he is a romantic thinker
But far beyond his time
He understands our ability to think
Not a free floating soul
But is deeply rooted in our physiology
Subject to our emotions
Shaped by our motivation and body
He understands this
But he also believes that the only way to solve the problem
For us humans, it becomes close to God
And create its own value
He will create his own value
Called "Superman"
This is what the Nazis used to arm their superior national ideologies
Nietzsche's philosophy
We all know what happened
Obviously nothing good happened
I also spent a lot of time reading a lot of Carl Jung’s books
It is through him
And Jean Piaget, a developmental psychologist
I just started to realize our clear thought system
Is deeply rooted in something like a dream
This dream is through a complicated way
Affected by our behavior
We often don’t understand what we show through our actions
If this is not true
We don’t need psychology, sociology or anthropology
These are unnecessary
Because we have fully understood ourselves
And obviously we are not
We are far more complicated than we know
This means that in our behavior
There are too many things we don’t know
A part of the dream that surrounds us with clear cognition
Formed by observing each other’s behavior
And tell it into a story and pass it on to all generations
Extract the behavioral patterns that shape human nature
And try to show it
Partly through imitation
But also through drama, mythology, literature and art, etc.
Show what we are like
So we can understand what we are like
This is what I read from the "Bible" story
At least part of the cognitive process shown in the Bible
It is hesitant, one-sided, clumsy and contradictory
This is one of the reasons that makes this book complicated
But from it I also interpret that humanity is in the animal ancestors
The struggle has found a way out
Then realized what it means to be human
And this is a very difficult thing
Because we don't know who we are
What are we or where do we come from
Life is an uninterrupted chain
Can be traced back to 3.5 billion years ago
It's pretty incredible
The ancestors of everyone here
Have successfully reproduced for 3.5 billion years
It's pretty incredible
We grow from the soil and silt
Become what it is now
We realized but failed to know
And try to figure out who we are
A series of stories we have told for 3000 years
It seems to me that there is a deep meaning
When I study the "Bible" story to some extent
Started with a beginner mentality
This book is really a mystery how it was made into a book
Why should it be written and why should we save it
Why does it happen to inspire a culture
For two thousand years and changed the world
What happened and how did it happen
It can't be obvious
There is one thing in the sloppy comments on religion that bothers me
That is they don’t take this phenomenon seriously
This is a serious phenomenon
Especially because people have the ability to get religious experience
But no one knows the reason
You can stimulate religious experience in various reliable ways
You can do it by stimulating the brain
Of course it can also be achieved through drugs, especially psychedelics
It can induce a close union with the divine very frequently
Only God knows how long people have used hallucinogenic drugs
It's about 50,000 years, maybe even longer
It is used to induce a
A close connection with the divine
We don't know anything about it
When we discovered psychedelic drugs in the late 1960s
It shocked everyone deeply
So that it was immediately classified as illegal
And it is forbidden to use it for research for nearly 50 years
It’s no wonder because no one can think of it
Jung was a scholar of Nietzsche
But he is also a sharp critic of Nietzsche
He was cultivated by Freud
Freud began to collect the information we have
This information is about the concept of people living in dreams
It was Freud who polarized the subconscious view
Now we take it for granted to a point
So that we don't realize
How revolutionary this view was at the time
For Freud's ideas
We used to go to the rough
Now when we mention Freud, we only consider his fur
Because this is the part that was abandoned
But many of his discoveries
Have become part of our current popular concepts
Include a point of view
That is your perception, behavior and thought
Are all influenced and shaped by subconscious motives
But not under your control
It's so weird
This is the psychoanalytic theory
One of the most disturbing things
Psychoanalytic theory can be understood like this
You are a loose collection of active sub-personality
Each of them has its own set
Motivation, perception of emotion and logical basis
And you have limited control over them
You are like a collection
Inside are some loosely assembled personalities
You know it well
Because you can't control yourself well
This is what Jung argued for Nietzsche
Refutation of the view that "we can create our own value"
Jung did not believe this
Especially after breaking with Freud
Because he realized that human beings are deeply affected by
Influenced by something outside the control of subjective consciousness
No one really knows how to define these things
Cognitive psychologists identify it as a computing machine
The ancients understood it as a deity
Although the facts are more complicated
Mars is considered the god of anger
When you are angry you will be possessed by him
This makes sense and it says what I want to say
This may be when you notice
What you want to say doesn't matter much
It's not only in you, everyone has
And it will last forever and even exist in animals
This is a transcendent mental entity
It was born in a whole nation
Just as a thought occupies the brain
This is a way to interpret it
This is a very strange way of thinking
But it does have its advantages
These things are gods in a sense
But it's not that simple
Jung is very interested in dreams
Then he began to understand the relationship between dreams and myths
Then he found his client’s dream
Always echoes the fairy tales
He once studied mythology deeply
He began to believe that dreams are the birthplace of myths
There is a continuous interaction between these two programs
From dream to story to narrative
When you can remember the dream, you can tell it as a story
Some people can remember all the dreams he had
There can be two or three in one night
I have had customers like this
They often have prototype dreams with a clear mythological framework
I think this situation is
More common among creative people
Especially when they were not emotionally stable at the time
Because dreams always tend to
Take up uncertain space
And focus on what you haven’t really understood
To visualize an unknown reality
So dreams are the birthplace of myths
This is a good angle of thinking
Because it is not so clear
It is trying to define something
Jung has a concept called "post-Freud"
There is a hidden dream
Internal review mechanism for true information
Jung didn’t think so
He believes that dreams express reality to the best of their ability
And this is still fully articulate
Perceptible understanding
Think about it, don’t you think an idea came to mind?
It's obvious
Bang this is something you never wanted
What does this mean
Just a thought that flashed through my mind
This explanation is ridiculous too
There is no use at all, where did the idea come from
Oh nowhere just appeared
It seems that this is really not a strict explanation
You may think about the ideas you have in mind
So where did these ideas come from
They are often the thoughts of other people
People who have been dead for a long time
Partly like this
Like the words you use to think
From the mouth of someone who has long since passed away
You are under the influence of your ancestors
This is a way to understand it
Your motivation emotion
And the body are communicating with you
And these are achieved through dreams
Dreams are the birthplace of ideas that can be fully expressed
They are not rootless trees
They all have a developmental origin
And only God knows how long that origin is
Even for example, I said "I am conscious"
Chimps don’t even say that
About 7 million years ago
We parted ways with the chimpanzees from the common ancestor
They have no knowledge that can be articulated
Almost no self-expression ability
There is almost no self-awareness and we are not at all like this
In the course of 7 million years
We must work hard to figure out all this
I think a part of it is an ancient story
Performance and record
I think especially the oldest stories in "Genesis"
This is what we are going to start deciphering
Some ancient natures of mankind
Are included in these stories
In my opinion they are very enlightening
Give a simple example
There is a concept of "sacrifice" in the Old Testament
Quite brutal
The story of Abraham and Isaac is a good example
Abraham was asked to sacrifice his son
This is not like a
What a reasonable god can make
God in the Old Testament
It is often cruel, ruthless and arbitrary
This is what gives this book life
It is certainly not edited by a committee
Because a committee will consider to avoid offending anyone
In short, Jung believes that dreams are the birthplace of thoughts
I have been expanding this idea
Because there is something that makes me curious
You have a dream and then find someone to interpret the dream
You can dispute the correctness of the explanation
Just as you can argue about the explanation of a movie or novel
It’s really hard to judge its accuracy
This is also part of the reason for the criticism of postmodernism
According to my observation, people will show a dream
And then we can occasionally
Extract real and useful information
But this person doesn't seem to know
But there was a glimmer of insight
For me this is a signal
Mark something we accidentally discovered
That is before someone
Split something combined
It can reround the broken mirror
Like a good story
Or a good theory can do the same
Things are all at once
At the same time a small light
This is what I use at home
Signals to determine accuracy and dream interpretation
When I was just married
I often quarrel with my wife
I'm very impatient in my heart
Then I will shoot the case
Get upset about what we are arguing about
Then she will go to sleep, which is really maddening
I'm annoying why I can't sleep
Gnawing nails in a hurry
And she was asleep beside me
I'm really going crazy
But she often dreams
We will discuss her dream the next morning
We can solve the crux of the previous argument
This is really very useful
Even though it was so quarrelsome before
So I was convinced by Jung
Tell me about his dreams, myths, dramas and literature
View of the connection
Makes sense to me
The same goes for his views on the relationship between people and art
I know an aboriginal sculptor
He is a Kwakwajakwa tribe
His works include
Wood carving totem poles and masks, etc.
I also collected some at home
He is a very interesting person
Almost illiterate
And focus on
This ancient tradition that has continued for 13,000 years
He speaks the original language
And he is illiterate
Makes him think a bit like
People who lived in the pre-writing period
People in the pre-text period are not stupid
They just can't read
Their brain organization is very different from ours
I once asked him where his carving inspiration came from
He told me that I got it through dreaming
You have all seen Haida masks
Know what it looks like
His ethnicity is closely related to the Haida ethnic group
Basically the same style
He said he would dream about animals and remember dreams
He was still talking to his grandparents in his dream
They will teach him how to carve
This happens often if he encounters problems in carving
His grandparents will appear in the dream
He will discuss the problem
In his eyes the animals he wants to carve
Is to live vividly in imagination
It’s not difficult to understand. First of all I have no reason not to believe him
He is a very upright person
And I don’t think he has any motivation or scheming
To make up a story like this
He doesn't make sense to do this
I don’t think he will talk to others everywhere
Because he also thought it was a bit crazy
When he was a kid he thought he was crazy
Because he always dreams of these animals
He is not what he wants to show off
It makes me very fascinated
Because i can recognize
Shows an unbroken tradition in him
We don’t know this tradition at all
How did it pass on for thousands of years
Partly by oral delivery and memory
Partly by performing it in a theatrical form
Part of it depends on imagination
How illiterate people store knowledge
Totally different from us
We don't remember anything
We all write in the book
But if you come from an oral traditional culture
Especially if you have been trained in oral tradition
You will have all the information in your head
So that you can speak
Then you can tell these stories
And can really understand them
Modern people can't think of what's going on
I suspect that there may not be more than two of you
Able to recite 30 lines of poems fluently
The purpose of poetry is to enable people to recite
This is why we have such a literary form
So that people can memorize it and keep it in their minds at any time
But now we don’t do it anymore
Closer to home, let's go back to Jung
Jung values ​​the value of dreams very much
I know dreams can tell what you don't know
How is this possible
What do you think of
Tell what you don't know
How can it make sense
First of all why can't you understand it
Why is it displayed in the form of a dream
It’s like there is something in your body
Things you can't control
Dreams look like real life to you
There is a strange kind of person who can have lucid dreams
In other words, they can remain partly conscious in their dreams
But most of the time you are lying down and sleeping
And this crazy and complicated world is inside you
Showing but you don't know how it happened
You can't do it when you are awake
And you don't know what it means
What exactly is going on
This is what you can learn from psychoanalysts
Such a terrible thing
You can see it from Freud and Jung
You will start to really recognize
Something in you is controlling you
Instead of you controlling them
You can do a little bit of mutual control
But there is always some kind of "spirit" display
Let's just say so
The spirit in your body determines your behavior
Just spend your life like this and you can't control it
What is this? Is it random?
Some people claim dreams
It’s just the result of a random reflex
I think this theory is really nonsense
Because dreams are not random events at all
Dreams are very organized and very complicated
It's not like snowflakes on the TV screen
Or the noise on the radio is actually quite complicated
I often see people who can dream a series of very coherent dreams
These dreams have a complete narrative structure
To some extent, they are very mature stories
So that theory doesn’t make sense to me
I think it's useless to say that
So I want to take this phenomenon seriously
There is such a situation in my dream
You dreamed of the future and you managed to realize it
It seems not a trivial matter
Or you had a nightmare and then realized it
Because people do
Like if they are determined to get revenge
And full of resentment and hatred
These will show up in bad fantasies
Dream first and then people put it into action
It is full of power
The whole nation can be involved in the collective dream
This is what happened in Nazi Germany in the 1930s
That is really an extraordinary sight that shocked the world
The same thing happened in the Soviet Union and other places
You have to take these things seriously
You need to find ways to figure out what happened
What Jung thought the dream might contain
More than clearly understood so far
I think the artist is doing the same thing
People go to the museum to admire the paintings
Whether it’s Renaissance painting or modern painting
They are not very clear about the appearance of these paintings
I've been to a museum in New York filled with Renaissance art
Are all great painters and even the greatest
I think the collection in that room may be worth a billion dollars
Even its value far exceeds this
Because there are about 20 paintings that are priceless
First of all, there is a question because these paintings are so valuable
Why in the largest city in the world
Will build an exhibition hall for these paintings
Why people from all over the world
Want to visit here
What are they doing
One of the paintings is "Assumption of the Virgin", which is beautifully painted
What a shining artwork
There are about 20 people standing in front of this painting and watching
What are they doing they don't know
Why do they go to the Holy Land in New York
Visit the painting specially
They don't seem to understand
Why is this painting so valuable
I know the status of this painting is extraordinary
But this raises another question
Why is this item's status so high
What is so extraordinary about them
We are weird creatures
I tried to figure it out
Where did the information in the dream come from
Must have its source
You can think of it as a revelation
Because it's like something out of nothing
And contains new knowledge and enlightenment
You didn't make it, it just appeared
This is one thing I want to take seriously
I am a person with scientific thinking
And I'm still a very rational person
Before I seek any other type of explanation
I tend to explain things with reason and experience
I'm not talking about everything related to divinity
Can be resolved
It can be resolved into another form
Such as the evolutionary history of biology, etc.
But as long as it can be resolved
I will do it
But I will keep other phenomena in a metaphysical state
Because they cannot be defined
In this category
I will define it as mystical and religious experience
These are things we don’t understand at all
The artists will observe each other as well as people
And then they show what they see
And pass this information to us
It taught us how to see and observe
We don't necessarily know
What we learned from them
But we did learn something
At least we acted like we were learning something
We watch movies non-stop
Read stories and immerse yourself in the fictional world
This is a work of art for many people
The art world is a living world
If you are a creative person
Then this point is particularly correct
It is the creative artists
Is promoting the development of human knowledge
First they will do this with their artwork
They are testing on the edge
Dancer, Poet, Visual Artist
And the musicians are doing this
But we are not sure what they are doing
We are not sure what the musicians are doing
What are they doing
Why do you like music
It will give you a deep hint of the meaning of things
no doubt
When you go to the concert, you feel an upsurge
This is a kind of religious experience
Especially when people really cheer up
And push the whole group forward
There is something very strong in this
But I don’t understand
This is not easy to understand
Music is very regular
And is regular on many levels
I don't think this is irrelevant
Because reality is also regular on many levels
I think music expresses reality in a basic way
We will be controlled by it and participate in it
This is part of what makes this experience so exciting
But we don’t really realize what we do
We did it without thinking and this is also nourishing people
Especially young people, many young people enjoy music very much
Where they get their own meaning
And the source of cultural identity
Everything that can nourish people
Are inseparable from the connection with music
Because it is part of their cultural identity
This is really a strange thing
But the question is still not answered
Where did the information in the dream come from
I think it passed
We observe everyone’s behavior patterns
We have been observing
We also observed
Part of our cultural history
This is what is deeply embedded in fictional works
Such as about good and evil
The story of the bad and the good and love
These are the typical modes of existence of people
And affect us deeply
Because they represent
What we do in this world
What we learned about
Individual information about yourself and others to visualize it
In the long river of time
There will be waves of behavior patterns of some people
Great dramas are also staged in the crowd over time
The artists observed and realized the meaning
They will record it and tell us
Then we have a clearer understanding of our behavior
A great playwright like Shakespeare
We all know that his works are all fiction
Then we will say that the fictional works are not real
But think about it
It may be as real as a number
Numbers are abstracted from potential reality
But there is no sane person
Would say that the numbers are not real
You can even think like this
Numbers are more real than things show
Because this abstraction is too powerful
When you master mathematics you have a killer
You can use math to move the whole world
Abstract is not more real than concrete reality
This is not obvious
When you watch a movie like "Hamlet"
When such fictional works
You will think it's not true
Because this is a fictional work
But you feel like wait a minute
What is the explanation
Maybe it's more real than non-fiction works
You need a story to tell yourself
This story to be told also needs
About you and each of you
This story will abstract it and show it
This is the key part of human experience
This is what is abstracted from the noisy matrix
People get infected because they can recognize
It shows part of their mode of existence
This is the correct way to understand it
Accompanying these ancient stories
It seems to me that this process has been carried out for thousands of years
It's like we observe ourselves first
Then extract some stories like
We imitate each other and show it in the drama
Then we extract some essence from these dramas
Repeat and complete the process
God knows how long we spent
I think part of these stories
Someone has traced some fairy tales back to ten thousand years ago
It exists in a relatively unchanging form
In my opinion, the archaeological evidence must
Shows those very old stories
Like the stories in the beginning of the Bible
At least a story as old as them
It may be deeply rooted in prehistoric history long before them
You may ask how can you be so sure
I can answer at least part of it
That is, the ancient civilization will not change quickly
They stay the same, this is the answer
Their information is passed on from generation to generation
They stay the same
We know that there are archaeological discoveries and some rituals are almost complete
Lasted for nearly 20,000 years
Someone found in a cave in Japan
Which has a certain kind of
The bear worship ceremony also has the characteristics of Western Europe
So these things can last for a very long time
We are observing each other in this world
Then the problem is coming
How long ago did we observe each other
In a sense the answer to this question is
Since the existence of a creature with a nervous system
And this is a long time ago
Hundreds of millions of years have passed
May be longer
We have been observing each other throughout this time course
Trying to figure out what each other is doing
Some of this knowledge is already built into your body
Like this is why we can dance with other people
Understanding is not an abstract concept that you understand
It’s what you show in your behavior
This is what children are doing when they learn to chase and fight
They are learning how to in a harmonious way
Integrate yourself with the bodies of others
So as to learn to work together and achieve goals
And these are manifested through their bodies
This is not abstract knowledge
They don't know what they are doing
They did that anyway
We can even move our body
Used as a display platform
We have been studying each other for a long time
Analyze what we are doing and what we should do
Here is a more basic question
If you want to survive in this world
You have to behave appropriately
What does it mean to be so decent
What can you do about this
This question is right
This is what we all want to know
How do you survive in the world
This is not how the world is made up
We one yard into one yard
How do you survive in the world
This is an eternal problem for humans
I guess we are the only one
The species that really asked this question
All other animals just do anything without thinking
And we’re not like this. It’s our own problem. We have to be aware of this.
We have to say it, God knows why, but this seems to be the case.
Our behavior is shaped by the world and society
Shaped into something we don’t understand but we can use it as a model to emulate
We imitate it in the story and imitate it with our body
This is the source of dream information
Dream is involved in this process
Observe everything and try to express it systematically
It tries to get the signal from the noise
And depicted in a dramatic form
Because a dream is a little drama
Then you have a chance to talk about what dreams are
Then you will get systematic knowledge
I think the existence of the Bible is
It's like this between dreams and systematic knowledge
Explore in the story of the Bible
The meaning helps us understand
Also suppose Nietzsche is right
Jung and Dostoyevsky are right
Then there is no cornerstone provided by this self-understanding
We are lost
This is very bad
Because in this way we will be vulnerable to mental illness
Those who firmly oppose religious ideas
Seems to think so
If we give up immersing in the potential dream
We can immediately become like
Rationalists like Descartes and Bacon
Become a very clever, clear, rational and scientific person
I don't think so
I don't think there is any evidence to support this
I think we will lose our minds sharply
So that the most bizarre mystery in Catholicism
Seem to become relatively positive and rational
And I think this is already happening
This is the general concept
For you there is an unknown world
You don't know anything about it
It's like an ocean
Surround the island where you are
Something like this
It is chaos itself
You are acting in that world
But your behavior is not known to you
There is much more in your behavior
What you can understand
Jung made a point
I liked it when I first understood it
He said that everyone is acting out a myth
But few people know what their myth is
You should understand your myth
Because it might be a tragedy
Maybe you don't want it to be like this
This is indeed something worth thinking about
Because your behavior pattern shapes your character
God knows where you got it from
Part of the reason is biologically inherited from your parents
This is burdened by you unintentionally
This is how the philosophy of your society makes you
And it's aiming you somewhere
Is the place you are being targeted for suits your wishes?
This is a good question
This is part of self-actualization
We know we don't understand our behavior
Almost all your arguments with others are related to this
Such as why did you do that
You will come up with some
Ambiguous reasons to explain your behavior
You are like wandering in the dark
You want to give yourself a reason
But can't do it completely
It's very very difficult
Because you are a complicated animal
It’s just that I have a clear mind
Your existence is far beyond your control
You can put something into action
This can be regarded as an ability
Then you will imagine what you put into action
I also think about what other people are doing
There is a lot of information in your actions
Then this information is transformed into dreams
Then presented in the form of art mythology and literature
This contains a lot of information
And part of it is translated into clear thoughts
Let me give a simple example
I think part of it is reflected in "Exodus"
When Moses wrote the law
He was wandering in the desert with the Israelis
They sway and worship idols
Began to become rebellious during this difficult time course
Moses climbed up the mountain
And get great revelation from God
He was inspired by the enlightenment and finally went down the mountain holding the law
Moses acted as an arbiter in the desert
I know this is a fairy tale
He keeps on
Mediation between people who have problems
Keep working hard to maintain peace
What are you doing when you try to keep the peace
You will try to understand what peace is
You have to apply some principles
What are these principles
Ok you don't know
These principles are to make people satisfied
So as to make peace by shaking hands
Maybe you need to try 10,000 times
In order to slowly understand which principles can bring peace
One day it will flash in your mind like a revelation
So these are the rules we have been following
This is the Ten Commandments
This is the place to start
Moses stepped forward and said
This is basically what we have been doing
It’s just that it’s now compiled into a law
This is the entire historical process condensed into a single story
But obviously this is how it happened
Because we already have a written law
Under a good legal system
The law germinates from the bottom up
This is how the common law system works
A single judgment is based on existing principles
Then clarify it and include it in the legal system
The legal system is what you put into practice
This is why it became a legal system
This is why if you are a good citizen
You will act in accordance with the legal system
The legal system contains principles
So the problem is coming
What are the principles that guide our behavior
I think when you initialize
The deep meaning of God in the eyes of ancient Israel
That’s what they meant to point out
This is not a good enough explanation
But imagine when you are a chimpanzee
At the top of your society
Have a strong ruler
It represents power even more than this
Because keeping a chimpanzee at the top of the hierarchy
It takes more than physical strength
It's far more complicated
You can say that this ruler revealed a certain principle
Then you will say if you know ten authority figures
This principle can be more brilliant
Then you can extract an authority concept from it
You can extract a concept of power
Then you can separate the concept from the crowd
We have to do this sooner or later
Because we can say that power in a human context
We can also imagine what this means
But it is separated from any concrete representation of power
Why on earth are we doing this is too complicated
If you are an orangutan and the powerful one is another orangutan
This is not an abstract concept
The problem is to imagine
We all live under various hierarchies
Some of them lasted for hundreds of years
We are trying to figure out what the guiding principles are
Try to extract the core of the guiding principles
And express it in a mode of existence
Something like this this is god
This is an abstract ideal model
It manifests as a form of personification
It’s okay because in a way
We are all trying to figure out what is
Means to be functional and socially decent
And the essence of the capable individual
We are trying to figure out what it means
You need a concrete avatar
You need to abstract an ideal model
So you can put it into practice
Then it can make you understand
What does this substance mean
This is our intention
This is the first hypothesis to some extent
I am going to talk about some characteristics of this abstract ideal model
This ideal model has been shaped by us as God
But this is the first assumption
The ideal model of philosophy or morality first presents itself as
A real behavioral pattern
This is a typical characteristic of an individual
Then it became some individuals
And then abstract from these individuals
Finally you have this abstract concept
And this is very important
Here is an example of its political significance
We can say that
There was a debate between the early Christian church and the late Roman Empire
That is whether an emperor can become a god
Truly deify it and enshrine it in the temple
You can now realize why this happened
This is something proud of
A man at the pinnacle of an extremely concentrated hierarchy
He has power in the world
Christian answer is
Never assign a specific ruler
Confuse with the principles of rule itself
This is simply wonderful
You can understand
How difficult is this?
Even if it’s a powerful person
Have to submit to a certain divine principle
Can't think of a better word
Even the king himself must obey this principle
We still think so because we firmly believe
Our President and Prime Minister cannot be above the law
No matter what the legal system is
There must be one
Principles that even leaders must obey
If even this is missing, you can think
You haven't even lived in a civilized society
Because your leader will suddenly
Transcendence and omnipotence
This is clearly in the Soviet Union and
What happened in Nazi Germany and other places
Those in power can be said to be lawless
You should succumb to god
What does it mean
We need to split it up and analyze it
But part of the meaning is
Even if you are a ruler you have to obey
Principle of domination itself
Then the problem comes again
What is the principle of governance?
I want to say on this issue
We have been searching for a long time
This is what we are going to talk about next
Ancient Mesopotamians and Ancient Egyptians
There are some very interesting things on this issue
Dramatic view
Let me give you a simple example
Once upon a time there was a deity called Marduk
Marduk was once a deity in Mesopotamia
Imagine this is what happened
An empire was established in the post-Ice Age
That's 1-15,000 years ago
All the tribes have gathered
These tribes have their own deities
Have their own ideal image
But they started to occupy the same territory
One tribe has deity A and the other has deity B
And one of them can destroy the other
Let’s suppose that God A wins
This is not so good
Because you might want to trade with these people
Or maybe you don’t want to be in war
Reasons like losing half of the population
Then you are in an argument
Whose god is
Which ideal model will take the first place
This seems to be in myth
Portrayed as the battle of the heavenly gods
From a practical point of view
This is more like a continuous conversation
You believe this i believe this
You believe that i believe this
How can we merge
You will take away deity A you will take away deity B
Then you might get from both
Extract a deity C and then you say
Deity C has the characteristics of both deity A and deity B
Then other tribes started to join
Deity C also took over these deities
Marduk is an example. He has many names
He has 50 names and some of them
At least part of it belongs to its subordinate god
These names symbolize
The various tribes gathered to create the entire civilization
This is a model of abstract ideals
Part of the process
You will think this is important
This works because your tribe is still alive
Then we draw on the strengths of both
If we can do it
Then extract a
Can include more abstract concepts of both parties if we can do it
There is something interesting about Marduk
I will introduce you some of his characteristics
He has eyes all around his head
He is the king of the gods recommended by the gods
This is the first feature
Pretty awesome
Marduk
Because they face a terrible threat
Something like a combination of a beast and a flood
Marduk probably said
If they choose him as the head of the gods
He will stop the scourge
Save them from extinction
This is a serious threat
It's the chaos itself that makes it comeback
The gods agreed
Thus Marduk became the new main god
He has eyes all around his head
Spit out the spell
He will also take the initiative when he fights
The god against him is called Diamat
We need to know this
Because of the word "diamat"
Related to the word "Abyss" in English
The abyss is the beginning of "Genesis"
God created the chaos of order
So it is closely related to this story
Marduk took his all-seeing eye
And the ability to vomit spells strikes
And Diamatt went hand in hand
Diamat seems to be some kind of ocean dragon
This is a classic St. George story
Punish the dragon
Marduk chopped it into pieces
And created the world with her corpse
This is the world that humans inhabit
The emperor of Mesopotamia is Marduk descended to earth
As long as he is a good Marduk, he can sit on the throne
This means that around his head
Have eyes and vomit curses
He must talk appropriately
At this time we began to understand the essence of leadership
Because what is leadership
This is the ability to recognize the situation at hand
I might even have to watch six ways and listen to all directions
Maybe you need to use words decently
The ability to turn chaos into order
Only God knows Mesopotamians
How long did it take to understand this
All they can do is to dramatize it
It's really wonderful
And it's not obvious
Chaos is really a strange thing
This is the chaos that God wants to solve at the beginning of time
Chaos is both psychological and de facto existence
It cannot be accurately described in other ways
The moment you face chaos
When you are hit hard and lost
When your world falls apart
When you encounter something that pierces your heart
When your dreams are shattered and betrayed
Chaos emerged from it trying to swallow everything
No doubt this is too heavy for you
It drags you into the habitat of evil dragons in the underworld
In that situation
What you have is the ability to look around with round eyes
And you need to do your best to speak carefully and speak clearly
And if you are lucky enough
You can survive the storm
It took a long time for people to figure this out
In my opinion this view is from
Established in the survival criteria of our ancient ancestors
Maybe this happened tens of millions of years ago
Because when we are still using the same cognitive system
This reflects the deep anxiety in our hearts
At that time this system was used
Representing snakes and other predators
We are all flesh and blood
We develop the ability to abstract things
Abstract language
Singular abilities
But we still retain the deep cognitive system
That existed when we were animals
We have to use these existing systems
Emotional and
Part of the reason for the formation of the incentive structure
We can demonize
Part of the reason for the enemies who disrupt our code of conduct
Because we recognize them as predators
We follow the same cognitive system
This is the chaos itself threatening us all the time
This is 60 million years ago
Those snakes climbing on the tree where we live
This is basically the same system
Part of Marduk's story
Is about using insight and words
The story of dealing with the most imminent threat
Some of them are real world threats
And some are psychological threats
The threat levels of the two are comparable
But the psychological threat is far from abstract
But we are still using the same system to represent them
This is why you freeze when you are frightened
You are a prey
You are like a rabbit
I saw something coming to eat you
You are frightened and paralyzed
You become a stone statue
This is what happens when you see a snakehead
What happens when Medusa
You will become a stone statue
The reason you are paralyzed is
You are still using the predator detection system to protect yourself
Your heart rate rises and ready to move
We are all upset by this system
Take the story of Marduk as an example
Its purpose is if something upsets you
Like the horror of the chaos that threatens you
Serpentine beast of the underworld
Your best strategy is
Organize language with eyes wide open
Then go out and face the strange shape to create a new world
This is really shocking
When I read this story and started to understand it
Really initiating
This is really a profound insight
And we also know that
Because in psychotherapy we know
It's better to face fear bravely than
Let fear come to your door to improve your body and mind
If you are a psychologist, part of your work
Is to smash those fears into small pieces
The things that upset them
Then face them one by one to conquer them
You are conquering in your heart
This process in the strange and chaotic world
The above are all building background
We haven’t even started talking about the first sentence in the Bible
But the above are all building background
We extract from the entire historical process
This series is full of false repetitions and weird stories
And we have accumulated ideas from history
This is the best thing we can do
I know there are other religious traditions
But at the moment i don't care about this
Because we can use it as an example
This is the best result we can achieve
I hope everyone can
Review these stories with an open mind
Then observe if there is something we really need
I hope to be able to do this
Like I said before
I will deal with it as rationally as possible
Let’s start with the following point of view
We know that there is something similar to the unknown
We act in it like animals
They just act without thinking
They don’t imagine that we start here just by acting
We start with action
And then began to be able to express our behavior
Then tell in words how we behave
This gives us the ability to tell stories
Because this is the meaning of the story
Tell how we behave
You know this because what happens when you read
The image will come to mind when you read
The characters in the book are moving in the form of images
This is one step away from putting it into practice
You don’t do it because you can abstract it
You can behave without taking action
This is amazing
Partly due to the development of the prefrontal cortex
This is the part of human abstract thinking ability
You can extract the performance of the behavior from the behavior
And control it before putting it into practice
That's why you can think
Then can summarize the behavior pattern
You can experiment in a fictional world before you practice
Not to die out of stupidity
You can let this abstraction express death instead of yourself
This is why you think
It is also part of the purpose we want to achieve through the story
What do i want to achieve
I want to end this 12-session lecture series
I know more than when I started
This is my goal because I have already said
I'm not instilling you what I know
I just want to try to figure out some things
What I am doing is completing part of the process
So I started from my perspective
Do my best to do this
I came prepared but I want to work hard to stay in
The edge of my ability is here I just can sum up knowledge
Keep making it clear and investigating
I hope this is what I am
This is what I want to achieve
It seems that there are still people interested in it
Let's achieve this goal together
I planned so
The intention is
Discover something in the foundation of this strange civilization
This civilization was successfully built by our efforts
But in my opinion it’s already at stake for more than one reason
Maybe we don’t know it so easily
Throw it all away, I think this is a huge mistake
And it was abandoned because of resentment, hatred, resentment
Ignorance of history and jealousy of others
The desire for destruction and so on
I don't want to fall into that situation
That's really not a good idea
We need to be more down to earth
I wish, let's take one step at a time
Ok so how do i proceed to do this
First I will look at this issue from the perspective of evolution
As far as I know, the universe has been 15 billion years since its birth
The earth is 4.5 billion years old
Life was born 3.5 billion years ago
A creature with a well-developed nervous system
Have existed for 300 to 600 million years
60 million years ago
We are still small mammals living in trees
60 million to 7 million years ago
We came up and down the tree to live on the ground
At this moment we separated from the chimps
The emergence of modern humans was about 150,000 years ago
Civilization was also born after the last ice age
It was about 15,000 years ago
Not particularly long
This time period is the part I want to study
I want to know why we are what we are now
Need from the origin of life itself
Start to observe the continuing complexity of life
Which must have real utility
Because we share some characteristics with other animals
Even simple animals like crustaceans
Crustacean nervous system and
Our nervous system has many similarities
This is worth understanding
I think from the perspective of evolution
I think this is a matter of thinking about it
Very grand and extraordinary angle
Because the time span is incredible
This is really amazing
Think about living at the end of the 19th century
And the people in the mid-19th century
I really think this world is only about 6,000 years old
15 billion years of history is much longer than this
This is more magnificent
But in a way it’s more terrifying and alienated
Because the universe has become so vast
It’s easy for humans to see themselves as trivial beings
Sojourn in a dark corner of the Milky Way
Among hundreds of millions of galaxies
In this time span
You can easily think of yourself as trivial
This is a real challenge for people
I don't think it's a good idea
Because I feel conscious
Far more limited than what we thought
This is still something we have to solve
My way of thinking is psychoanalytic
It means i believe
People are a collection of sub-personality
And these sub-personality are alive and not a machine
They have their own opinions, desires and perceptions
They also have their own arguments and emotions
They are like your low-resolution representations
When you are angry
It will look a lot like your very low resolution form of expression
It just wants to eat angry
Drinking or having sex
It's yourself
But it was reduced and concentrated in a specific direction
All these incentive systems
Are very old and powerful
They play a decisive role when we express ourselves
As Freud pointed out with the concept of "self"
We must figure out
How do we get these potential
Animalistic motives and emotions
And how to civilize it
In order to coexist on the same territory
Instead of tearing each other to pieces
And the latter is probably
Default settings for chimpanzees and humans
So I really value this point of view
That is the loose collection of we are all spirits
There is a place in the Old Testament that says
The fear of God is the beginning of wisdom
I think the meaning of this sentence is similar to the above point of view
That is do you know
You can't completely control yourself
There are other factors behind the scenes
As the ancient Greeks thought
They think humans are the playthings of the gods
This is how they conceive the world
What they say is almost the same
They think that existence is not endogenous to us
Power is driving us
In a way this is the force we are obeying
But not completely obey
But you can obey them
And they are controlling our destiny
This is the view of the ancient Greeks
It will make you humble so that you can understand it
Because so much is happening behind the scenes
You are driving a very complicated car
But you don’t know much about this car
It has its own motivation and methodology
Sometimes you think it’s something
But in fact it is quite different
This phenomenon is very common in psychotherapy
Because the psychiatrist is helping others to solve
Of the behavior pattern it has always shown
First they will describe the symptoms and realize the symptoms
Then they may start to explore the cause
They don’t know why they did that
At first they must have
Memory that leads to this behavior pattern
This pattern must be recalled
Perform analysis and evaluation
Then patients must consider another way of behavior
It's really complicated
Let's talk about the literary perspective after the psychoanalytic perspective
There is still a postmodernist concept of literature today
Of course there is this view of the world
If you interpret a complex literary work
Such as the works of Shakespeare
You can interpret it in countless ways
You can read it word by word and sentence by paragraph
You can also interpret the whole work
The way you interpret it depends on how many books you have read before
Also depends on your worldview
It depends on many many things
How educated you are or how uneducated you are
Countless things like that
This creates infinite possibilities for potential interpretation
The postmodernists are a little bit arrogant here
If there are countless ways to interpret a literary work
How can you be sure of any of these interpretations
Would be more reasonable than other interpretations
If you are not sure about this
How can you know which works are great
How would you know that these works are not in power
Tools to sustain its rule
This is a very typical postmodernist view and very cynical
It has its truth
But the point is to be based on some real things
Yes you can read things endlessly
I want to show you something briefly
We will talk back later
have a look
This is the best thing I have ever seen
Each line at the bottom represents a verse
The length of the line and this verse
The number of times it is quoted in other scriptures is proportional
So this is the first hyperlinked book
I'm really serious about this
Obviously you cannot activate the hyperlink with a mouse click
But this is a book of hyperlinks through and through
This is because the people who created these stories
Assuming these stories are the end
In fact, it means the end cannot affect the beginning
This is the rule of time
What happens now will not affect what happened ten years ago
Although it is actually possible, no matter what
You can reinterpret the past and they will change
Anyway, let's not talk about this
Technically speaking, the present cannot affect the past
But this is not the case for a literary work
Because when you write to the end, you know what the beginning is like
When you write the beginning or modify the beginning
You also know what the ending is like
Then you can weave the whole story
It can be seen from this picture
A total of 65,000 cross references
For this book, this is a really amazing visual presentation
Why it is so profound
Why is this book so profound
Let's imagine
How many ways can you take in these hyperlinks
This can be said to be a journey that never ends
You will never reach the end
Among them are permutation and combination
Every word depends on other words
Every sentence depends on other sentences
Of course not exactly
But 65,000 is not a small number anymore
This seems to make
Postmodernist comments are more correct
What do you know from such works
How can we sum up an authoritative explanation?
Seems impossible
But there is a problem in my opinion
That is what postmodernists have
Apply this view to the whole world
They will say look at this text is too complicated
You can't come up with an authoritative explanation
What about the world
The world is much more complicated than a text
You can infinite ways
Observe the world
Then how do we know a way
Would be better than the other
This is a good question
The postmodernist answer is that we have no way of knowing
This answer is not very good
Because you will fall into chaos in this situation
You can't know anything
This is not a good thing
Because knowing nothing about things is not a neutral and harmless event
It can cause anxiety and depression
If things are so chaotic that you can't start
Your body will return to the default critical alert mode
Increased heart rate and immune system stops functioning
You will run out of oil
You will age very fast
Because everything around is beyond your control
This is the existential crisis
It makes people feel anxious and depressed
Not only that we found
Our nerve structure is like this
If we don’t set a goal and move towards it
We will not experience any positive emotions
It’s not that reaching the goal makes us happy
If you have achieved something, you will know
When you reach your goal
This little game is over
You need to invest in another game
So this is what Sisyphus’s god punished
But it does show
Reaching the goal does not become the motivation to drive you
Because it will crash the whole game
That's it when you graduated from university
It's like you were the king of the mountain the first day
Then you will be working at Starbucks for five years
Humans are really strange creatures
We have goals
And will be more energetic when advancing towards it than when reaching the goal
The meaning is that you must have a goal
Is that you must have an explanation
It also means that the more lofty your goal
This is a way to think about it, the better your life will be
The funny thing is that you've heard this
Even when you were very young
Others tell you to be a good person
For example, don't lie and then you will think
Why should i be a good person why not lie
Even a three-year-old will ask that
By the way, smart kids will learn to lie earlier
They wonder why they don’t distort the structure of the facts
In order to meet my specific short-term needs
This is a great question why not
Since you can escape punishment
Why do you have to follow ethics?
Besides, this can be one step closer to what you want
Why not do this
Really a good question
But it is not obvious
This seems to be closely related to what I said before
If you make yourself unstable
Things will become messy, which is very problematic
If you don't have a lofty goal
What you have is just a trivial pleasure
And these pleasures can’t keep you
This is not good because life is really hard
Filled with too much suffering and complexity
When it's over, everyone dies. It's painful
Without a lofty goal
What do you use to resist these
You can't help you despair
When you despair
Things will deteriorate quite quickly
So there is the concept of lofty goals
It is necessary
This is the food necessary for people to survive
This is not some mysterious food
It is the lofty goal
And what is the lofty goal?
Part of it has been concentrated in
Marduk's story is in
That is to always focus on speaking appropriately and face the chaos
Build a better world
It's something like this
This is the lofty goal
It will make you stand upright
Instead of shrinking into a ball and thinking about your own existence
So you can do something worth the time
Just to give you on this planet
A miserable situation
From the perspective of literature
You can explain a text from many angles
But this is not right
This is where the postmodernists go wrong
What you are looking for in a text
The same principle is to be pursued in the world
Is enough order and direction
We have to consider
What does adequate order and direction mean
You don't want to suffer too much
So that your life becomes unbearable
This seems pretty self-explanatory
Pain is to justify yourself
I think pain is the fundamental reality
Because no one will argue about it
Even if you say you don’t believe in pain
Won't make you feel better when you suffer
You still believe
You cannot eradicate it with logic and reason
It exists fundamentally
And it’s actually very useful to recognize this
That is you don’t want to suffer more
Unless it is absolutely necessary
I think it goes without saying
But you might say wait a minute
The problem is not so simple
Not only do you not want to suffer more than necessary today
And tomorrow next week
Next month and next year
So no matter what you do now
It's best not to endanger yourself in a year
Because it will backfire
This is the problem of short-term pleasure
I regret a lot of hastily
Everyone understands this truth
What you do will work right now
To be sustainable tomorrow, next week, next month and beyond
So you have to think about the future
Humans can do this
Consider your future
This is not much different from taking care of others
I remember there was an episode in The Simpsons
Homer drank a quart of mayonnaise and vodka
Marge said that you shouldn't do this
Then Homer answered that it was the future Homer’s question.
Fortunately I am not that person
It's so funny
But we need to work hard to overcome this
Future you
Is a bit like another person
And handle you properly
Relationship with the future self
And figure out how
No different from other people
So we can relieve the constraints
The explanation you extracted
Not only protect you
Free from pain and give you a goal
And it must be done in an iterable way
So it can continue over time
And this process also requires the participation of others
So you can work with them
In a way that reduces your own pain
Do something with them
People are not so forgiving
They have a choice
They don’t have to deal with you
They can also deal with other primates
If you behave inappropriately
At least if you cross certain boundaries then you will be left out
People are spreading information to you all the time
About how you need to interpret the world
So they can tolerate you when they are by your side
And you also need this because if you are isolated from the world
You will be insane until death
No one can stand long loneliness
Without constant feedback from others
We can't stay sane
This is simply too complicated
You are bound by your existence
You will also be bound by the existence of others
At the same time the world is restricting you
I read this point from "Hamlet"
That's i should jump off the bridge
So that my explanation can end soon
This doesn't seem to work very well
An explanation is constrained by the reality of the world
It is also bound by the reality of others
Your reality restricts it over time
In a tightly defined space
Only a few explanations make sense
This is part of the reason why postmodernists went wrong
This is also how people work hard to create artificial intelligence
When making smart machines
Part of the reason why it must be limited to one entity
From this we can see that if we don’t materialize it
You can't make any smart machines
This is part of the reason I just described
You need to constrain the system
Otherwise the entire system will be submerged
In the ocean of infinite interpretation
Almost like this
This is its literary aspect
Moral aspect
Ethics is only related to behavior to me
To some extent I am an existentialist
That means I firmly believe
What people believe in truth
It's the behavior, not the words
There are many definitions of truth
Truth is a very broad word
You can think of objective truth
But behavioral truth and objective truth are consistent
As far as I know, what you should do is not the same as the facts
People are divided on this
But I think the reason should be the same
Think of it this way, you stand in front of a wilderness
You can see the wilderness
But the wilderness won’t tell you how to pass it
You can walk through it in countless ways
So you can't extract
An inviolable guide to guide you
How to act in front of all kinds of facts
There are so many facts that you will lose direction
But you need to know how to avoid pain
Need to know what your goal is
So you need to use some explanatory structure
To superimpose on objective reality
This is what we want to focus on
The essence of explanatory structure
I have given a hint before
We have taken it from the observation of our own behavior
Extracted from observations of others
The part we extract is
With our concretized nature
This is formed in the past billions of years
We see the infinite plane of fact
Then we imposed a moral explanation on it
Moral explanation is how to act on objective existence
This is related to the sense of security
Because you just don't want to make things too complicated
And this is also related to the goal
We are moving creatures
We need to know where to go
In general everything we care about
Where is the future
This is what we need to know
Where are we going and what are we doing and why
This is the same as "Objectively what makes the world?"
Are two different things
This is a completely different question
It requires a completely different answer
As far as I know this is the realm of morality
That's what your goal is
In a sense, this question is about the ultimate ideal paradigm
Although you have some trivial ideals
Something will emerge from it
More coherent and integrated
Applicable and practical things
This brings up another point
When you think of literature and art
You will think they are not very grounded
They are illusory and divine
Seems impractical
And i'm a real person
I think from the perspective of literary aesthetics and evolution
Part of the reason to review these books is
I want to extract something of practical value from it
Because I have a rule when I lecture
That’s what I won’t tell others that is useless to them
I think knowledge is a tool
It is something to be implemented in this world
We are creatures that use tools
Our knowledge is the tool
We need to use tools to work in this world
We need tools to regulate our emotions
To improve things
To end the pain as much as possible
Come calmly and stand on its own feet
You need tools to do this
So in this series of lectures
I don't want to do anything unrealistic
I want you to leave
Can have some systemic things
And it's something that can be used immediately
I am not interested in abstracting for the sake of abstraction
It needs to be reasonable it has to be meaningful
Because the more restrictions on the theory, the better
I want everything to have a context
B followed by AA and B before C
This way is understandable
No unnecessary leap of faith
Dealing with us and people like the Bible
The relationship between a set of books
Another problem is that you are being asked
To believe in something other people can’t believe
That's not good
Because it seems to me it is a form of lies
Then you have to void the whole thing
Because in principle this whole thing is about truth
If you want to swallow a lot of lies
To start your pursuit of truth
How can you achieve any achievement
I don’t want to leave any uncertainty fundamentally
Or I don’t want to leave any
I don't need to be left uncertain
Because then I can't go deeper
It must have a reasonable meaning
I also don't want it to work with
Known scientific facts contradict
Although science is constantly changing
That is a dangerous parameter
For example, if a solution doesn’t make sense in the theory of evolution,
Then this is not a good solution
Then there is the last point of phenomenological perspective
Modern people think reality is objective
We are very strong
But we don’t experience reality like this
We all have our experience field
But this is a very difficult thing to understand
Although it should be the most obvious
For phenomenologists, everything you experience is true
They are very interested in your subjective experience structure
You have your subjective experience, you also have everyone
But these experiences have something in common
For example, you will all experience the same set of emotions
We can recognize typical emotions
We can’t even communicate without the typical motivation
Because you don't know what the other person is like
In this case you have to explain endlessly
Nothing you can take for granted
But you can do
Phenomenology is
In the center of my sight and hands
Those are clear but to the edge of this range
They disappear
Phenomenology is about how things smell and taste
And their importance
Then in a sense you can also say the same
Phenomenology studies
The importance of matter rather than matter itself
From a phenomenological perspective
A basic fact is that everything has meaning
Even if you are a rationalist, cynicist, nihilist
Saying that everything is meaningless
You still face the problem of "pain"
Pain is meaningful, it weakens your argument
Meaning cannot be escaped
You can largely destroy the positive part of it
But you try hard
Can you figure it out from the negative side?
Good luck because it doesn't work at all
"Bible" story is about phenomenology
I think all fictional works are like this
It is dedicated to clarifying the nature of human experience
This is different from the objective world
It is also a form of truth
Because your field of experience is real
Also quality
So the question is what is quality
The representation of reality in ancient times is
A strange mixture of observable phenomena
This is what we call objective facts
At that time, there was also a projection of subjective facts in the representation of reality
I will show you
How do Mesopotamians see the world
Their world model is a disc
If you walk into a clearing in the dark
What can the world look like to you
Isn't it just a disc?
There is also a dome on this disc
This is basically the worldview of the Mesopotamians
The person who wrote the opening stories of the Bible
View the world in this way
The water on the dome is obvious
Because it always rains, right
Where does the water come from?
There is also water around the dome
The whole disc is made of land
There is water flowing under the ground
How do you know this
You can drill down to get water
This water comes down from the ground
How else can you get water
What's under this fresh water
Further down
If you go to the edge of the disc
You will see the sea and that is salt water
So this is a dome surrounded by water
The dome covers a disc
Fresh water flows under the disc
There is salt water further down
This is roughly the world in the eyes of the Mesopotamians
It is a mixture of observation and imagination
Because this is not the real world
Just what the world shows
This is a completely credible cosmology
The sun rises and sets over the dome
It doesn't look like something is going around
How could anyone think of this
Obviously the sun rises and sets
Then it moves below the world and then rises again
Nothing more obvious than this
This is on the cognitive level
The weird interweaving of subjective fantasy and visible phenomena
All related to the story of the Bible
The universe theory is exactly the same
It is semi-psychological and semi-realistic
And the psychological part is actually real
I understand that in the Bible story
Phenomenological truth is indeed worth it
Poor fundamentalists
Trying to stick to their moral structure
I can understand why
Because it really organized their society and soul
So they have to rely on
But for the complexity that constitutes truth
They don’t have a very precise concept
They tried to put the "Bible" story
Fetched in the field of scientific theory
For example, to promote creationism
Treat it as another scientific theory
Isn't this futile
The person who wrote these stories
Not a scientist at all
There were no scientists at all
Of course not much now
It’s really hard for us to see things from a scientific perspective
This requires a lot of training
Outside the lab
Scientists don’t use scientific thinking
Of course they don’t use scientific thinking very much in the laboratory
Because you have to be peer reviewed and criticized
Scientific thinking is really hard
No matter how the people who wrote these stories
The way of thinking is very similar to that of playwrights
It's like Shakespeare's way of thinking
But this does not mean that there is no truth in it
It just means that in the concept of truth
You need to be more precise, this is okay
There will always be some practical truths, right?
We want to figure out what these truths are
Because we need to live
Maybe need not suffer too much
So if you know the "Bible" story
And what other stories try to show is
Past experience of conscious individuals
The structure that the conscious individual has experienced
You may enter a completely different field of understanding
It eliminates the gap between the objective world and the religious story
Painful contradiction
Let’s take a look at the structure of this book
The first thing to mention about the Bible is
It's a comedy
Comedy has a happy ending
This is weird
Because Greek mythology is almost always tragedy
And the Bible is a comedy
Have a happy ending
Everyone is alive and there is a heaven
How do you think about it is another matter entirely
I'm just telling you the structure of this story
It can be said that there is a heaven at the beginning of time
Then there were some disasters and people fell into history since then
History is to limit death pain and self-awareness
But there is a pattern
Or imply a model of nation-building
It can surpass those
This is also what time points to
This is the concept of the story
What’s interesting is that the Bible also has a story
Because it was not a book when it was written
It's a combination of many different books
These books can be combined to form a story
This is really extraordinary
The question is what this story tells
How it became a story
Is there any reason
It constitutes a dramatic record of self-realization or abstraction
I mentioned this before
The idea of ​​formulating the image of God is an abstraction
This is how we will proceed to interpret it later
Because I said before
I will not simplify unnecessary
I want to say that I know the evidence of true religious experience
Is beyond doubt
But it is also unexplainable
So i won't explain it
I want to treat it as a fact
Then I will pull out of it
For example, we first treat it as a fact and a mystery
Then we have to look at it from a rational perspective
Another example is the initial formulation of the concept of God
Is an attempt to abstract the ideal model
Then we consider it as an abstract consideration outside of realisation
That's good enough
It would be amazing if this is true
But I don’t want to kill a boat with a stick
This is a set of books launched by many editors and editors
What does this mean
Means that many people are involved in writing
Formed many different books
All mixed together
Especially the first five books were compiled by a specific group of people
I suspect they are under a single political organization
Integrate tribal traditions
And try to connect what they describe
They learn from each tribe’s traditions
And don’t miss any case easily
Because they seem to be precious
Looking at the people who compiled these stories
It must be precious
Because they can't tolerate excessive deletions
But they want to think it makes sense to some extent
So that the book will not be completely illogical and absurd
Many people participated in writing
Many people also participated in the editing
There are many people in a long time course
Combine it
Documents like this are very rare
And just because we have a document like this
There are enough reasons to regard it as
An extraordinary phenomenon
And there are enough reasons to work hard to understand
The message it tries to convey
I said this is the world’s first hyperlinked book
This is indeed very intriguing for a long time
The Old Testament
Or the Hebrew Bible has four bases
Four stories we know come together
The first is the priest document
The name of God in it is called "Ilohim" or "Ilshade"
I think "Yil" is also the origin of the word "Allah"
It is often translated as "God/God" or "Gods"
Because the word "Elohim" is in the first few books of the Bible
Is in the plural
This background is newer than Jehovah’s documents
The reason I say this is
The first chapter of Genesis is the first story
It was not created in the same period as the second chapter of Genesis
Chapter 2 contains the content of Jehovah's version
It contains the story of Adam and Eve
It is older than the first book in the Bible
But they decided to put the new version first
I think this is because it deals with more fundamental abstractions
Reasons like this
It deals with the most basic abstract concepts
About how the universe was formed
Then it was connected to the appearance of the human environment
It seems that the logic behind it is like this
The four-character God’s name is used in the Jehovah literature
Obviously people don’t think so
But we know that its pronunciation is similar to "Jehovah"
This version contains an extremely anthropomorphic God
Have a human appearance
This point starts in the fourth chapter of the second chapter of Genesis
This is the description of heaven and earth
It also contains the story of Adam and Eve
The story of Cain and Abel The story of Noah's Ark
And the story of the Tower of Babel "Exodus"
And "Numbers" also contains priest documents
It also contains the law
To show in the form of the Ten Commandments is only in form
Because the Ten Commandments are like an abridged form of the law
Then there is the original copy of the Elohim literature
It contains the story of Abraham and Isaac
Which involves a heavenly hierarchy that includes angels
It also talked about the journey of leaving Egypt and gave the covenant
This is the concept of society
This refers to Israeli society
This idea is based on a contract with God
A list of regulations
Part of it is the ten commandments
And there are more extensive regulations than this
The last one is the original text of Deuteronomy
It contains most of the law
It also contains what is called the history of Deuteronomy
It is related to "Genesis" and "Exodus"
"Leviticus" and "Numbers" independent
At least we understand this
The controversy about these scripts is really all-encompassing
I just touched on the knowledge of this academic field in general
But usually people think
The Bible has different authors in many different periods
My conclusion is drawn through research text analysis
I.e. try to find the same style
A long story with the same citation
People are arguing about it because
It is obviously difficult to reproduce ancient things
That's roughly it
This is the collection of opinions about these initial questions
It's important to know this
It's like a collection of stories
It’s strange to understand the first part of Genesis
I want to turn to some content in the New Testament
This is the central element of Christianity
This is indeed a very strange idea
And it will take a long time to analyze
The following is what John the Baptist said about Christ
He said "there was a way in the beginning" (about 1:1)
This sentence is somewhat related to the first chapter of Genesis
"In the beginning
"The Tao is with God and the Tao is God" (John 1:1)
These three sentences have a lot to analyze
Because they all seem to have no meaning
"In the beginning
"The Tao is with God and the Tao is God" (John 1:1)
So the first question is what does this mean
"There was Tao in the Beginning" (about 1:1)
This is actually "Logos"
And the image of Jesus is the visualization of Logos
The view in the Gospel of John is that Christ is the Son
No matter what
He is not in a certain time and space
As a carpenter in a barren land
But outside of time and space
Still exists in an eternal form
This is what existed in the beginning
For me, logos represents
What modern people mean when they talk about consciousness
Similar to this but more than this
It's like consciousness
Its ability is to comprehend and communicate
The implication lies in the existence of creatures
Especially from a phenomenological point of view
Life is experience
The existence of creatures is inseparable from consciousness
It's like saying that consciousness shoots a light on the dead object
Transform it into a creature
What else exists without consciousness
No one can experience anything
If no one can experience anything
Is there anything else?
This is a problem
The answer given in this book is no
You have to think of consciousness as
An indivisible element of reality
This is the necessary condition for reality to exist
Of course this will raise questions about the definition of reality
But the reality mentioned here refers to
As i mentioned
Refers to the weird mixture of subjective experience and the world
But the depth of this question is more than that
If no one has experienced it
There can be no obvious way to determine what exists
The whole concept of time will fall apart
At least in terms of perceiving the flow of time
The concept of size has essentially disappeared
Because there is nothing to measure it
Causality also seems to cease to exist
We can't understand the consciousness is really ignorant
We can't understand
What gives us the light of life in our body
What happened in the Old Testament
At least in part
Is to connect this consciousness with divinity
Now think about it, is this a reasonable proposition?
This question is complicated
But at least we will find that this description is a bit problematic
Because there is a miraculous experience
And existence depends on consciousness
People always prevaricate after just explaining it
But there seems to be no good result
And this is something to consider
I think it is worth considering
People don’t like to be seen as unconscious
Their reaction will be intense
If someone thinks you are unconscious
You will be upset
If someone thinks you have no free will
Because that means you are only fully confined to
In your behavior
There is no remedy
At the same time you are not responsible for your actions
Our culture the law of our culture
Are built on
People are consciously based
People have experience
Make decisions and be responsible
This embodies the element of free will
You can raise objections from a philosophical point of view, of course it’s fine
But the point is that this is how we behave
And this is the premise of our legal system
There is something deeper in this
Because you are restricted by law
But the law is also restricted by you
That is to say in a well working
Under a reasonable democratic system
You have intrinsic value
This is the source of your rights
Even if you are a murderer
We must also say that the law cannot do whatever you want
Because you have a divine side
What does this mean
Part of its meaning is
Part of you is conscious
Ability to communicate
Like you are a self-contained world
You can use it to contribute to others, which is valuable
You can learn new knowledge to transform the structure of society
And can invent new ways to deal with the world
You can do it all
This is part of you
This involves this
The concept of logos
For the absolutely chaotic reality
Logos are indispensable
Beyond expressing its existence as reality through experience
This is an amazing view
Because it allows your consciousness to act in the universe
An indispensable role
You can refute it
But you can’t simply erase it
Because first
We are the most complicated thing in existence
At least in the known world is quite complicated
We are incredibly complicated
There are many universes outside
But there are many universes within
Which of the two is greater is hard to say
Unless you use something irrelevant
Such as relative size
But this is really not a strict plan
No matter what you have
Experience reality and the ability to transform reality
This is a very strange thing
You can imagine the future in your imagination
Then you can show it in practice
Participate in the creation process
This is an angle to think about this issue
That's why
I think the first chapter of Genesis is related to this point of view
That is, human beings are all created in the image of divinity
Whether it is a man or a woman
But it’s interesting that feminists are always
Criticize Christianity as an outright patriarchy
Of course they will criticize everything as patriarchal
So this is rarely a whimsical idea
But I think this is definitely a miracle
The beginning of a document is straightforward
Without any hesitation
Said that the brilliance of divinity is connected with Tao
Tao gives birth to life again
It is reflected equally in men and women
This is really awesome
Like I said before, you will definitely think
Will you take this seriously
What you want to ask is
What will happen if you don't take it seriously, right
Read "Crime and Punishment" by Dostoevsky
This is among the existing works
The best inquiry about this thinking strategy
In Dostoevsky’s Crime and Punishment
The hero's name is Raskolnikov
He believes that other people have no intrinsic value
Of course he can do whatever he wants
Only cowardice will stop him
If the value of others is just an arbitrary superstition
What else is left
Why can't I act recklessly every time
This is the way mental patients think
So this is what Raskolnikov did
He killed a very disgusting person
And he had a good reason to kill her
He was half-starved and a little mentally disturbed
And obsessed with an ideology
This is depicted very well in the book
And he discovered one thing after killing her
That is Raskolnikov before and after the murder
Pan Ruo two are completely different because he broke a commandment
He has committed a serious violation
"Crime and Punishment" is what I know
The best inquiry into this situation
This situation is if you firmly believe that there is no
What will happen in any divinity
Most people I know are staunch atheists
I also understand why they become staunch atheists
They will not be like Dostoyevsky
Such people raise objections
As far as I know, I didn’t find that in Crime and Punishment
What logical loopholes exist
I think he is very accurate in psychology
At this point Dostoyevsky is really a strange man
In his other book "The Demons"
Depicts a political situation
No different from where we are now
Some of them firmly believe
Rationalist utopia and atheistic views
They have great energy
Then they set off a revolution
These are all powerful views
Among them is a character named Stavrokin
It also guides practice with such a premise
That is that human beings have no inner essence
No intrinsic value
This is another wonderful inquiry
Dostoevsky predicted the development trend of society
If you really follow this road
He became a true saying after ages
After reading "The Demon", you will find it incredible
Or "The Enchanter" depends on the difference in translation
When you read Alexander Solzhenitsyn’s
You will feel this way in "Gulag Islands"
The first book is a fictional work and a prophecy
And the second one is to take a look
What happened here is exactly what Dostoyevsky predicted
The reasons are the same
This is really amazing
So the problem is
Do you really object to the following views
A Consciousness is an indispensable part of the universe
B Consciousness is likely to be considered divine
C Does it manifest in everyone?
And if you are not a criminal
Ask yourself if you don't act accordingly
Ask yourself what it means
Does it reflect reality? Is it a metaphor?
Maybe it's a complicated metaphor
We use it to organize our society
It's very possible
But even a metaphor, it is true enough
So that we play with it regardless of our own safety
And it also takes a long time for people to figure out
This is the first chapter of Genesis
But I might end here
Because it's half past nine
But we didn’t even mention the first sentence
I want to read something
Make an introduction for the next lecture
I will start from a set related to divinity
Pick some reading
Let’s go back to the first few words of the lecture
By the way, I don’t know that in the end we can cover
How many "Bible" stories
Because I'm trying to figure out my clues while teaching
There is a concept in Christianity
Call the image of God the "Trinity"
The element of the Father
Element of the son
There are also elements of the Holy Spirit
It’s a bit like the traditional spirit
Humans are the latest incarnation of this tradition
This traditional living body and the spirit
Makes the relationship between the individual and the spirit possible
I want to quickly go over
Some classic and metaphorical attributes of God
So that we can have a rough idea later
In order to understand that when we look back at the first chapter of Genesis and
Discuss what God is talking about when he shapes creatures from chaos
There is the Father's side here
So God is like a father
You can make a contract with
You can also make an agreement
But think about it now
It's like money
Because money is an agreement with the future
The world we build
Is to enable you to negotiate with the future
I don't think when we are doing this
Didn't realize it at all
You can see the future as real when you act
Because there is a traditional spirit that makes you
Treat the future as an object of negotiation when acting
This is why you will make sacrifices
We have a long history of sacrificing
But now it’s only done on a psychological level.
We know you can sacrifice the valuable things in the moment
I hope you are with some kind of
Negotiating something that represents a transcendent future
This is an amazing human discovery
No other creature can do this
Treat the future as real when you act
Knowing that you can negotiate with reality
And it really works
This is incredible
It will respond to sacrifice
It also answers prayer
By the way, I didn't say these are true
I'm just talking about what this rough concept represents
It will punish and reward
It will judge and forgive
It is not natural
Judaism and Christianity
A bit strange
That is that God and nature are not the same thing at all
No matter what god is
He is partly represented in the logos
And logos are separate from nature
I think it's like consciousness
It is abstracted from the natural world
It created the Garden of Eden for mankind
But drove us out for the sin of disobedience
It can only be viewed from a distance and not playable
It gives us free will
Stay away from it is hell
To stay away is death
It is revealed in dogmatic and mysterious experience
It is the law
This is probably the Father’s side
Look at the side of the son
It creates order in chaos
It kills the dragon and feeds the people with its flesh and blood
It finds treasure to save chastity
It is the blood of Christ
It is a scapegoat for the tragic victim
Is also the savior of eternal triumph
It cares about the abandoned
It died but reborn
It is the king of kings
It is not a country
But at the same time fulfilling and criticizing the country
It came to the perfect apartment
It also pursues wonderland or heaven
It can save lives from hell
It also cares about the abandoned people
It is the foundation and cornerstone of rejection
It is the spirit of the law
Finally, the side of the Holy Spirit
It is similar to the human soul
It is the voice of the prophet
It's the murmur of consciousness
The truth of its words
It is inspired by music
It is the enemy of arrogance and resentment
It is the water of life
It burns without embers
It is a dazzling light
This is a very complete set of poetic metaphors
What do you say
It's all a glimpse of a transcendent ideal model
This is the right way to think about it
They are all glimpses of transcendent ideals
They also have clear meanings
While we are conducting this series of lectures
To a certain extent, it is also understanding the meaning
What we are talking about now
At least a brief description of these
"In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth" (Genesis 1:1)
We know that in the next story
It is closely related to logos
We know it is connected with Tao
Also connected with consciousness
And we also know
It is also connected to God no matter what he is
Then I will unfold a metaphorical picture
At least it portrays God in part
Now we are right
A little understanding of the existence of the creation world
"Earth is emptiness and chaos" (Genesis 1:2)
This is the prehistoric state of chaos and ambiguity
"Darkness
"God's Spirit is running on the water" (Genesis 1:2)
"God said "Let there be light" and there will be light" (Genesis 1:3)
We're going to end here
Because we are ready
To the beginning of this book
Took a tentative step
It’s important to organize your conceptual framework properly
So you can experience
The direction of travel and the possible meaning in it
Then i have done my best today
How to say it
Explaining this word painstakingly makes me feel
But this is not as simple as talking about it, so you know
It took a long time to reach this point
Not so unreasonable
At this moment you can finally realize a bit
About the meaning of this word
It is far from reaching
It is not
I thought I could go a little deeper than I currently
So be it, thank you very much